Okay, so let's summarize the four
predictive estimating methods.
So the ones that we've
talked about and the ones that
you need to know for the
exam are these four here.
Analges estimating,
parametric estimating, bottom
up and three point,
three point estimating.
Right, so analogous estimating,
remember this activity is similar to a
prior activity, so it's using historical
information.
So the advantage is,
it's quick and easy, but
the disadvantages, it
might not be very accurate.
right so just because it took us 20 hours
last time doesn't necessarily mean it'll
take us 20 hours this time but it's a
quick and easy ballpark figure parametric
estimating then remember parametric is
using first principle mathematics right or
a statistical relationship we're
extrapolating results right so the
advantage there then is because we're
always doing some kind of math then it can
be more accurate than an algus
if we have a lot of information
a lot of data then it can be
more accurate than an algus.
But the disadvantage is the parameters may
not scale.
So the example that I gave earlier,
just because it takes us one hour to lay
down 25 meters a cable,
doesn't necessarily mean it'll
take us 40 hours to lay
down 1,000 meters of cable.
So if the parameters don't scale, then the
estimate will be quite
inaccurate in that case.
Then you've got bottom-up estimating,
and a bottom-up estimate, remember,
is a phase.
very, very detailed estimate, right?
You're breaking your activities into
little sub-activities, right, you're doing
a granular level assessment,
and then also you're
rolling up each layer of the
work breakdown structure.
So it's a very, very accurate,
right?
The advantage is it will be, out of all of
these, it'll be the most accurate.
However, the disadvantage is, it's going
to be time-consuming.
We don't always have time to do such a
detailed bottom-up estimate.
And at the same time, you can
only do a real detailed bottom-up
estimate when it's a very
well-understood project as well.
And then three-point estimating,
right, and remember whenever generally
when we're talking about three-point,
we're talking about the putt, well,
if optimistic, most likely
pessimistic values are
accurate, three-point
estimating will be accurate.
If one of those values is incorrect,
three-point estimate
will not be very accurate.
And especially the most likely,
since you're waiting the most likely by
four, if the most likely
estimate is not very accurate,
then that throws off the
whole three-point estimate.
So a three-point estimating then generally
will be for well-understood activities
when you can easily
predict the most likely,
easily predict the optimistic
and the pessimistic.
Then it will be, the three-point will be
quite accurate.
But again, the disadvantage, if one of
those, you know, values are inaccurate,
the whole pert estimate is going to be
inaccurate.
So these are the four predictive estimating
methods that PMI ask about on the exam.
In reality, there can be many,
many more, but for the purpose of the PMP
exam, these are the four estimating
methods that you need for the PMP exam,
specifically for predictive questions.
Agile has their own estimating methods,
which we are covering in separate videos.